[
    {
        "question": "What is the length of the train?",
        "options": [
            "120 metres",
            "180 metres",
            "324 metres",
            "150 metres"
        ],
        "answer": "150 metres"
    },
    {
        "question": "A train 125 m long passes a man, running at 5 km/hr in the same direction in which the train is going, in 10 seconds. The speed of the train is:",
        "options": [
            "45 km/hr",
            "50 km/hr",
            "54 km/hr",
            "55 km/hr"
        ],
        "answer": "50 km/hr"
    },
    {
        "question": "The length of the bridge, which a train 130 metres long and travelling at 45 km/hr can cross in 30 seconds, is:",
        "options": [
            "200 m",
            "225 m",
            "245 m",
            "250 m"
        ],
        "answer": "245 m"
    },
    {
        "question":"A train is running at a speed of 100Kmph. A car is running on road parallel to the train’s track at a speed of 20 Kmph opposite to train. How much time will it take to cross the car if the length of the train is 100 meters?",
        "options":[
            "5 sec",
            "4 sec",
            "3 sec",
            "3.5 sec"
        ],
        "answer":"3 sec"
    },
    {
        "question":"A boatman takes 3 hours 45 minutes to travel 15 km downstream and takes 2 hours 30 minutes to travel 5 km upstream of a river. What is the speed of the stream of the river in km/h?",
        "options":[
            "2 km/h",
            "1 km/h",
            "6 km/h",
            "4 km/h"
        ],
        "answer":"1 km/h"
    },
    {
        "question":"A speedboat runs 6 km upstream in a river and comes back to the starting point in 33 minutes. The stream of the river is running at 2 km/hr. What is the speed of speedboat in still water?",
        "options":[ 
            "25 km/h", 
            "21 km/h", 
            "26 km/h", 
            "22 km/h"
        ],
        "answer":"22 km/h"
    },
    {
        "question":"A boat runs at the speed of 13 km/h in still water. If the speed of the stream is 4 km/h, how much time will it take to go 68 km downstream?",
        "options":[
            "5 h",
            "4 h",
            "6 h",
            "3 h"
        ],
        "answer":"4 h"
    },
    {
        "question":"A train is running at a speed of 100Kmph. A car is running on road parallel to the train’s track at a speed of 20 Kmph opposite to train. How much time will it take to cross the car if the length of the train is 100 meters?",
        "options":[
            "5 sec",
            "4 sec",
            "3 sec",
            "3.5 sec"
        ],
        "answer":"3 sec"
    },
    {
        "question":"Express 252 as a product of primes.",
        "options":[
            "2 * 2 * 3 * 3 * 7",
            "3* 3 * 3 * 3 * 7",
            "2 * 2 * 2* 3 * 7",
            "2 * 3 * 3 * 3 * 7"
        ],
        "answer":"2 * 2 * 3 * 3 * 7"
    },
    {
        "question":"Find the highest common factor of the following numbers: 4 * 27 * 3125, 8 * 9 * 25 * 7, 16 * 81 * 5 * 11 * 49",
        "options":[
            "180",
            "360",
            "540",
            "1260"
        ],
        "answer":"180"
    },
    {
        "question":"Calculate the HCF of 1.08, 0.36 and 0.9.",
        "options":[
            "0.03","0.9","0.18","0.108"
        ],
        "answer":"0.18"
    },
    {
        "question":"Three numbers are in the ratio 1:2:3 and their HCF is 12. The numbers are:",
        "options":[
            "4, 8, 12",
            "5, 10, 15",
            "10, 20, 30",
            "12, 24, 36"
        ],
        "answer":"12, 24, 36"
    },
    {
        "question":"The sum if two numbers is 528 and their HCF is 33. The number of pairs of numbers satisfying the above condition is:",
        "options":[
            "4","6","8","12"
        ]
    }
]